

# **Chrea Chanchhunneng**

SENIOR DEVELOPER

- Stueng Meanchey, Meanchey, Phnom Penh Cambodia
- chreachanchhunneng@gmaill.com
- ☐ https://chhunneng.github.io
- @chrea-chanchhunneng-11a833168
- https://github.com/Chhunneng
- https://gitlab.com/Chhunneng

#### **SKILLS**

**Project Management** 

••••

**Teambuilding** 

••••

Code reviews

••••

Problem-Solving

••••

**Troubleshooting** 

• • • • •

**Programming Languages** 

••••

**Excellent Communication** 

••••

**Decision Making** 

••••

**Cultural Awareness** 

• • • • •

Responsible

• • • • •

Algorithm implementation

• • • •

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented Software Development leader experienced in producing and updating systems. Optimizes structures and processes to accomplish customer targets and promote company loyalty. Expert in diverse programming languages. Bringing more than 3 years of experience leading website design projects, including gathering user requirements, producing code, creating mockups and enhancing designs. Focused on creating clean, robust code with exceptional security. Achieves compatibility targets while meeting and exceeding customer demands. Hardworking and passionate job seeker with strong organizational skills eager to secure entrylevel position in environment. Ready to help team achieve company goals.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN**

#### Intern

Jul 2019 - Dec 2020

- Developed, coded, modified and debugged application programs of varying degree of complexity with full independence.
- Assisted with creating cross-platform UI web components and built responsive applications using front-end frameworks.
- Helped code and test full-stack [Software]-based web application software based on Agile Scrum and Kanban approaches.
- Learned new emerging technologies and took initiative to offer technical direction and creative solutions.
- Delivered user support to clients to train, educate and answer questions.
- Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve site interactions.
- Developed e-commerce website to reduce cart abandonment rate, resulting in increased online sales after go-live date.

## **BACKEND DEVELOPER INTERN**

## Intern

Oct 2020 - Mar 2021

- Wrote high-quality code to meet customer requirements.
- Cooperated with front-end developers and other team members to design more cohesive and functional code.
- Adapted and understood Agile and Scrum methodologies.
- Designed, developed and tested software applications.
- Engaged with clients to plan, optimize and repair site issues and queries based on technology.
- Coded using Python, Django, Pytest with PostgresDB.

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

# **Highschool Diploma**

Hun Sen Oreang Ov High School Sep 2006 -Sep 2017

#### **GED**

Paññāsāstra University of Cambodia Oct 2017 -Oct 2018

# **GED**

Institute of Technology of Cambodia
Oct 2017 -Sep 2018

#### **GED**

Kirirom Institute of Technology

Nov 2018 -Nov 2022

#### LANGUAGES

**English** 

• • • • •

Khmer

••••

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

# Own Project

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Took initial concepts and developed project plans.
- Adjusted design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.
- Conducted unit testing to deliver optimal browse functionality.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards and online applications using Django, React and PostgresDB.
- Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms.

# **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

# Own Project

Jul 2021 - Dec 2021

- Adopted engineering best practices and delivered highest quality scalable solutions.
- Paired with fellow engineers to brainstorm ideas, debug problems and review code.
- Worked with customers to define requirements and troubleshoot issues and architected and implemented new engineering applications to meet needs.
- Designed and implemented scalable application programming interfaces.
- Developed complex software and systems deploying one or more programming languages.
- Created and maintained service desk diagnostics and job aids and reviewed with technicians to confirm clarity.
- Created powerful Content Management Systems to serve as interface for client.
- Performed development, debugging, optimization and automation to support implementation of products and applications.
- Understood full technology stack and underlying applications, services and databases, resulting in optimal program performance.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards and online applications using React Native, Hasura and QraphQL scripting.

#### STORAGE ENGINEER

# Freelancer

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

- Developed, implemented, supported and maintained data analytics protocols, standards and documentation.
- Designed and developed and analytical data structures.
- Developed and modified programs to meet customer requirements.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

# Freelancer

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

- Provided front-end website development using React, React Saga and other library.
- Ran debugging tools such as Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Coded websites using React, SCSS, TypeScript and Redux.

# **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- The top one of CS Cup Cambodia (Competitive Programming in Cambodia) for 2020 and 2021 with 1st rank.
- Resolved product issue through consumer testing.
- Collaborated with team in the development of all working.